Lukas Anderson

Address: Seattle, WA 98110

Contact: luke.anderson2010@hotmail.com

(206) 799-2858

I aim to grow my technical skills and ideally contribute to an environmental or humanitarian company. I'm a personable, curious and experienced developer with contemporary and diverse skills. I was a software tutor and tour guide before I began my career, showing my ability to communicate, lead, teach respectfully and meet the expectations of both my employer and the customer.

Skills

Javascript React.js Node.js Unit Testing (Enzyme) SQL

Java Spring RESTful APIs UX/Wire-framing Automation (Protractor.js)

Experienced in Agile Development, Micro-services Architecture, SaaS and Object-Oriented Design Principles.

Experience

TrackVia - Developer II - Front-end

January 2018 – April 2019

TrackVia is a leader in low-code business management solutions. They build and maintain a web application providing custom, integrated tools to manage client operations with no code necessary.

Improved client innovation by providing iterative application development through a sandbox feature

Optimized UX and QA Automation through standardizing feature appearance and code structure

Assisted custom client integrations by developing an API access and security management tool

Team-based (4) Kanban-Scrum fusion development (TrackVia application for project management)

Beeline – Full-stack Developer

December 2016 – December 2017

Beeline is a world-leader in contingent workforce solutions. Their primary service is a Vendor Management System (VMS) which connects businesses to candidate suppliers to fill vacancies.

Designed and built scalable micro-services with Docker & Kubernetes to provide data, visualizations and functionality to clients

Consolidated two login processes to streamline the authentication and authorization UX

Improved efficiency of candidate supplier usage by clients through building a scoring and metric app

Team-based (6) kanban development (JIRA)

INRIX – Front-end Developer – Paid Summer Position

June 2015 - August 2015

INRIX is a world-wide, industry-leading vehicle traffic optimization and data analysis company. It is partnered with auto manufacturers, such as BMW and Audi, through navigation applications; and municipalities, like Seattle DOT, through traffic-flow optimization and advisory applications.

Optimized business practices via aggregation, visualization and reporting of data for internal marketing Exceeded expectations in building an internal tool utilizing an internal RESTful Java API, JSON objects,

Charts.js and Bootstrap.js

Improved UX of customer-facing web application(SaaS): INRIX Insights – traffic data analysis tool

Team-based (7) agile environment (JIRA), cooperated with UX team utilizing Balsamiq wire-framing

Kombi Korp – Web & Mobile App Tester – Paid Summer Position

May 2014 - August 2014

Kombi is a Seattle-based start-up focused on digital signage and marketing.

Performed quality assurance with unit tests, automated REST tests (deployed with JenkinsCI for Linux), load tests with SoapUI against a MongoDB instance

Team-based (8) Scrum development using Git and JIRA

Education

BS Computer Science, Minors in Philosophy & Marine Science, Eckerd College

2016

About Me

When I'm not exploring the mountains or exercising, I spend my time writing, seeing live music or playing drums. I am an outdoors & environmental enthusiast. My first job was a Kayak & Dive shop for four years giving tours, educating the public about the oceans and working sales/customer service. I am decisive, organized and a solid communicator who actually enjoys writing documentation.

Other Experience

Eckerd College – Java Tutor

September 2014 – May 2016

Educated students 7 hours/week covering data structures, algorithms and design patterns

Eckerd College – Paid Student Developer

January 2015 - May 2015

Recommended by the Computer Science Department as a candidate for the position

Designed and optimized internal admittance system using Salesforce CRM in a unique and creative way Team-based (5) development using Wrike

Exotic Aquatics Scuba & Kayaking – Tour Guide & Sales

February 2012 – June 2016

Led kayak tours and assisted SCUBA dive ventures around Bainbridge Island, WA Sales, inventory management & customer service experience

Tampa Bay Aquatic Preserves – Volunteer

September 2015 – December 2015

Designed public outreach programs, organizational work and invasive species removal

Eckerd College Environmental Studies – Volunteer

April 2014

Built and installed Least Tern (bird) nesting platforms on campus

Student-led Trash Pick-ups – Organizer and Volunteer

September 2012 – May 2016

Coordinated and led trash pick-ups around Eckerd's shorelines